Javad Adib





Full Stack Engineer

Lives 15+ years with code and debugging as a programmer. A lover of microservice architecture due to the freedom of technology and scalability. Collaboration with dozens of specialists and teamwork led to the acquisition of valuable insight, particularly on e-commerce. Built infrastructures of over 7 multi-million dollar projects from scratch. The learner who knows how to learn. Open-source enthusiast.

mr.javad.adib@gmail.com



+98-935-726-9759



Iran

Professional Experience

Full Stack Engineer

Jibres Full-time

(2 years 7 months) 12/2019 - present

- Implemented an integrated cloud eCommerce solution for 1,200+ businesses containing website, app, PoS software, CRM, CMS, accounting software, ticketing system, and form builder.
- Joined the bug bounty program and introduced the new WAF that filters and monitors 99% of the attacks.
- Launched an automated app factory that generated the native android shopping app without coding in less than 10 minutes.

Full Stack Developer

Azvir Full-time

(2 years 4 months) 09/2017 - 12/2019

- Constructed an educational management system that serves four organizations, 500,000+ students, and 2,000+ teachers.
- Analyzed and database design from scratch. Design 150+ SPA functional modules with server-side rendering technique.

Full Stack Developer

Sarshomar Full-time

(2 years 4 months) 06/2015 - 09/2017

- Spearheaded the 15 members' cross-functional team, and launched a product that earned about 1M users in just a month.
- Built Siftal UI framework, Dash as PHP framework with MVC pattern, 2x the development speed by consolidated SPA.

Computer Lecturer

Teacher Part-time

(11 years 4 months) 06/2006 - 09/2017

- Taught 2,000+ students in web technologies courses, ICDL in 4 universities, vocational colleges, and private classes.
- Created and published tens of hours of unique free web and office video tutorials, which has led to an acquisition of skills by thousands of Persian speakers from around the world.

Software Developer

Mixa Full-time

(3 years 11 months) 08/2011 - 06/2015

Developed a cloud archiving solution that saves +1M docs annually and avoids wasting several tons of paper.

UI/UX Wordpress Developer

Freelancer Freelance

(3 years) 09/2008 - 08/2011

Designed and developed 40+ WordPress websites with HTML5 and CSS3, improved user experience, achieved a high SEO rank.

Volunteer work

Software Solutions for Business - Expert

WorldSkills

(5 years 3 months) 06/2010 - 08/2015

Tutored and trained three talents who have won silver and two bronze medals in national competitions; held the national team camp to attend WorldSkills Sao Paulo 2015.

Education

M.S. in Information Technology Management

Azad University Part-time, ABD

Expected in 2022

B.S. in Computer Software Engineering

Azad University Part-time

2014

Skills

Fully Proficient Web Technology HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP Language C, C++, C#, VB.NET, Node.js, TypeScript, Bash, Python Data Structure and Database MySQL, SQL Server, JSON, YAML

Distributed Cache Redis, Memcached

Web Service SOAP, REST API, GraphQL

Web Framework Express.js, Laravel, Symfony, Vue.js

Front-end JS Library Vanilla JS, jQuery, Alpine.js, React

CSS Framework Tailwind, Bootstrap, Semantic UI, Materialize

Build Tool Sass, Grunt, Gulp, Gradle, Webpack

Version Control System Git, Github, Gitlab

Test Driven Development - TDD PHPUnit

CI/CD Container Docker

Backend Web Server Nginx, Apache

Server Configuration Framework UI cPanel, DirectAdmin Network DNS, DHCP, HTTP, SSL, TLS, SMTP, FTP, MIME, SSH OS Windows, Ubuntu, Debian, CentOS, macOS, VMware ESXi Software Development Methodology Agile, Scrum, Kanban Collaboration Tool Jira, Trello, Zoom, Slack

Microsoft Office Specialist Excel, Access, PowerPoint, VBA Graphic Design Tool Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Figma Miscellaneous Cloud Development, RDBMS, QA, Analysis, SaaS, Object Orientated, A/B Testing, Crwal, Maintenance, OWASP, CORS, NPM, Composer, PWA, XML, XHTML, Twig, AJAX, SCSS, LEMP, LAMP, CLI, Wireguard, Accounting, VoIP, SEO, MVC, OOD, SOLID, Marketing, Teamwork

Awards and Honors

Membership

Iran's National Elites Foundation

2013

Silver Medal

WorldSkills Iran - IT Software Solutions for Business

Medallion for Excellence

WorldSkills Iran - IT Software Applications

2008

2009